<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Dr. Chris Gaskell</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Dr. Chris Gaskell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 01:04:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of the unified protocol for treating co-morbid health anxiety and depression: An empirical case study</title>
      <link>/blog/up-sced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 01:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/up-sced/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Aims: The Unified Protocol (UP) is indicated when patients present with comorbidity, but no studies have investigated the effectiveness of the UP with comorbid health anxiety and depression.
Method: An A/B single case design evaluated outcomes for a 27-year-old male presenting with health anxiety and comorbid depression. Following a 21-day assessment- baseline period, the manualised UP was delivered across a 42-day period containing seven intervention sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of compulsive buying disorder: Comparing the effectiveness of cognitive behavioural therapy with person-centred experiential.</title>
      <link>/blog/sced-cbt-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sced-cbt-buying/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Background: Outcome studies of the treatment of compulsive buying disorder (CBD) have rarely compared the effectiveness of differing active treatments.
Aims: This study sought to compare the effectiveness of cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT) and person-centred experiential therapy (PCE) in a cross-over design.
Method: This was an ABC single case experimental design with extended follow-up with a female patient meeting diagnostic criteria for CBD. Ideographic CBD outcomes were intensively measured over a continuous 350-day time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of transdiagnostic seminars to support patients with common mental disorders: A multi-service practice research network study</title>
      <link>/blog/up-sced/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 01:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/up-sced/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Background: This was a multi-site evaluation of psycho-educational transdiagnostic seminars (TDS) as a pre-treatment intervention to enhance the effectiveness and utilisation of high-intensity cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT).
Aims: To evaluate the effectiveness of TDS combined with high-intensity CBT (TDS+CBT) versus a matched sample receiving CBT only. Second, to determine the consistency of results across participating services which employed CBT+TDS. Finally, to determine the acceptability of TDS across patients with different psychological disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effectiveness of cognitive analytic therapy for borderline personality disorder: Utilizing a withdrawal experimental design to improve sensitivity to abandonment.</title>
      <link>/blog/sced-cat-bpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sced-cat-bpd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Objectives: A primary methodological weakness of the single-case experimental design (SCED) outcome studies conducted of the treatment of personality disorder with cognitive analytic therapy (CAT) is that they have failed to employ a withdrawal phase or cross-over design and so are deemed quasi-experimental. This study sought to implement a withdrawal design, in order to improve the internal validity of the study to make it a true SCED, and also in order to enable the patient to explore abandonment dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring how to deliver videoconference-mediated psychological therapy to adults with an intellectual disability during the coronavirus pandemic.</title>
      <link>/blog/ld-therapy-teleconferencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 01:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ld-therapy-teleconferencing/</guid>
      <description>Abstract     Purpose: The novel coronavirus and associated restrictions have resulted in mental health services across the UK having to adapt how they deliver psychological assessments and interventions. The purpose of this paper is to explore the accessibility and prospective acceptability of providing telephone and videoconference-mediated psychological interventions in individuals with intellectual disabilities.
Aims: As part of a service evaluation, a mixed-methods questionnaire was developed and completed by clients who had been referred for psychological therapy at an adult intellectual disabilities’ community health service in the north of England.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
